DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
While you guys were turning to stone, bleeding from your nose,
在你們石化、流鼻血
and getting engrossed in hunting for food,
沉迷於找尋食材時
I managed to find some patterns in the shifts of the dungeon.
我發現了幾個迷宮變動的固定模式
It's not like I wanted to be turned to stone.
別說得像是人家是自願想變成石頭
Hear, hear!
就是說啊…
The past three days have been very productive!
這三天實在是收穫滿滿啊！
Yeah, whatever.
好，知道了啦
One path gets blocked and another one opens up.
有死路出現後 相對地也會有相通的道路
It's basically this on repeat.
基本上就是這樣不斷重複
The number of doors, furniture, and types of buildings stay the same.
門戶和家具的數量 以及建築物的種類都不會改變
A house never transforms into a graveyard.
民宅不會變成墓地
The walls move in a clockwise spiral at regular intervals.
牆壁會定時往順時針方向渦狀移動
The positions of the stone statues and the directions they face are fixed.
石像的位置及方位都是固定的
Based on all that and more…
綜合其他規則…
I remember this street.
我對這條路有印象
That's the house where we ate the Dragon.
我們曾經在那棟房子吃過龍
Chilchuck, you're a genius!
奇爾查克，你好厲害！
Well, it's all in a day's work.
畢竟這是我的工作嘛
But this street…
不過這條路…
Exactly.
沒錯
It's where we lost Falin.
是我們和法琳走散的地方
There was a pool of blood and traces of something being dragged.
殘留著一灘血和拖曳過的痕跡
It's Falin!
是法琳的！
If those two catch sight of it, they'll get worked up for sure.
要是被那兩個人看到肯定又會動搖
How am I going to make them stay calm?
該怎麼讓他們冷靜下來？
Laios, look!
萊歐斯，你看！
What is this?
這是怎麼回事？
Listen! I get that there's a lot to be concerned about,
聽著！雖然有很多讓人在意的地方
but for now, let's focus on getting back to the surface and…
但我們現在還是優先回到地面…
Huh?
什麼？
The Dragon's carcass was here, right?
有炎龍殘骸的地方是這裡對吧？
It's vanished, without a trace.
已經消失得無影無蹤了
But this crack in the wall must've been made when the Red Dragon fell.
不過那道牆上的裂痕 是炎龍倒下時留下的吧
But even this crack is being repaired…
但裂痕也開始被填補起來了…
The magician's eye will be upon you.
魔術師的眼線要來了
Don't yell like that!
別突然大叫啊！
Just now, I saw…
我剛剛在那邊看到…
I think it's mana sickness again.
我好像又魔力暈了
Again?
又來了？
Ever since I used healing magic, I sometimes see and hear things.
我在使用治療魔法後 有時會出現幻覺和幻聽
You hear things?
幻聽？
Are you sure it's mana sickness?
那真的是魔力暈的症狀嗎？
What did you hear?
你聽到了什麼？
"The magician's eye will be upon you."
“魔術師的眼線要來了”
"The magician's eye"?
“魔術師的眼線”？
Could it be…
該不會是…
The sound of wings!
是振翅的聲音！
It's that Little Dragon!
是那隻小型龍！
We need to hide!
我們必須趕快躲起來！
Hide where exactly?
是能躲去哪裡啦？
This place is too exposed.
待在這裡太容易被發現了
We've got to run, Marcille!
我們快跑，瑪露希爾！
No, I know where to hide.
不，如果要藏身…
Inside the wall!
可以躲進牆壁裡！
Come on, you two! Hurry!
動作快！你們兩個也躲進去！
Is this…
這是…
Another one of her spells?
又是她施展的魔法？
Marcille, what kind of magic was that?
瑪露希爾，這到底是什麼魔法？
Cleaners?
清道夫？
What?
什麼東西？
Dungeon Cleaners.
迷宮清道夫
They're creatures, I think,
是會將迷宮內的垃圾清除
that keep the dungeon clean and fix up any damages.
修復迷宮破損處的生物
Exactly.
正是如此
I figured this wall wasn't completely set yet.
我猜想這道牆應該還沒完全固化
Up until this point is the original wall,
到這裡是原本的牆壁
and from here on are Cleaners.
這邊開始則是清道夫
Even the floor!
連地面也是！
Check it out!
看吧！
Even the wear and tear and tiny scratches are being recreated.
隨時間朽化的樣貌 和細小刮痕也忠實重現出來了
You can't tell the difference by sight.
肉眼根本難以辨別
Ugh!
天啊！
There are tiny things crawling all over the floor!
地上有一群小生物在爬行！
Gross!
好噁心！
They're all Cleaners.
這些都是清道夫
Any dungeon without them would fall apart in no time.
如果沒有清道夫，迷宮很快就會瓦解
They're not monsters and aren't harmful.
並非是魔物，算是無害的吧
They are harmful.
是有害的存在
These suckers often nibble on my tent.
這些傢伙常咬老夫的帳篷
They break down anything they think is in the way.
清道夫會把覺得礙事的東西 全都分解掉
They must've come to eat the remains of the Dragon and the explosion.
是為了吃龍的屍體 和被爆炸波及的殘骸而來的吧
They show up when the dungeon is damaged,
迷宮內部受損時清道夫就會出現
and their secretion prevents fires from spreading and further collapses.
用分泌液防止火勢蔓延和坍塌
Then they start devouring any scattered rubble.
然後開始吃散落在周圍的垃圾
They're not picky eaters.
並不挑食
Finally, they excrete secretions to fill in the broken areas
最後在殘缺的地方填入分泌液
and restore the dungeon to its former state.
讓迷宮恢復成原本的樣子
It's similar to how creatures heal.
和生物的自癒過程相同喔
All things considered,
所以說所謂的魔物
monsters act like the immune system, clearing out germs.
就像是把病菌排除的免疫組織
Who are you calling germs?
你說誰是病菌啊？
Is that also magic at work?
那也是一種魔法嗎？
Pretty cool, huh?
很厲害吧？
Good grief.
真是的
What's next, a magical digestive system?
接下來是否會有 魔法的消化器官登場啊？
I wonder what the dungeon would eat in that case?
那樣的話迷宮會吃什麼呢？
Thank goodness the bloodstains are gone.
幸好血跡消失了
Hey.
喂
Let's get moving before the dungeon shifts again.
趁迷宮還沒變動時前進吧
Right.
好
Stairs!
是階梯！
Finally, a way out.
終於可以出去了
Well then, how about we start preparing that?
那麼就在這裡做那件事如何？
Good idea. Let's do that.
好主意，我們做那件事吧
That?
那件事？
Oh, you mean that.
哦，我知道你是指什麼了
Huh? By that, you meant a meal?
不會吧？你們是指“吃飯”嗎？
I don't think there are any Tentacles on this level.
階梯上應該沒有觸手喔
You should've said earlier!
那就早點說啊！
You actually like that outfit, don't you?
其實你很喜歡穿吧？
I don't!
才沒有！
We've got so many ingredients, I'm not sure what to make.
食材如此充足，要做什麼好呢？
Maybe I can try using that.
試著用用看那個吧
Cook up some grain.
先把麥子煮熟
Is it the stuff from the third floor?
是在第三層撿到的那個嗎？
I was saving it for when we ran out of food.
為因應耗盡糧食，老夫先儲備起來了
Chop up some Cockatrice meat,
切碎雞蛇的肉
Dryad fruit,
樹精果實
Mandrake fruit and leaves,
曼德拉草的果實和葉子
and depetrification herbs,
以及除石化草的葉子
Season them and sauté.
在調味後翻炒
Spread a layer of cooked grain inside hollowed-out bricks.
把麥飯鋪在掏空的磚塊裡
Add the toppings and heat them, brick and all.
放上配料，連同磚塊一起加熱
And…
然後…
Huh? What's that?
啥？那是什麼？
A Cockatrice egg.
雞蛇的蛋
I brought one along,
雖然把蛋帶了過來
but it's been a bit tricky to use.
卻不太好用啊
Finally, pour on the egg sauce and
最後澆上蛋汁
it's ready.
就完成了
STONE-BAKED COCKATRICE CHICKEN AND EGG WITH SAUCE
（石燒雞蛇澆汁親子蓋飯）
Wow, what is this?
哇，這是什麼啊？
It looks delicious!
看起來好好吃！
If I'd stayed petrified, would they have used me to make this dish?
如果我一直處於石化狀態 是不是會被拿來做成這道料理？
The scorched grain is nice!
鍋巴真美味！
Try digging your spoon into the dish.
試著把湯匙插進容器吧
I used bricks made from Dungeon Cleaners.
老夫這次用上 以迷宮清道夫做成的磚塊
So we can even eat the dish?
也就是說連容器都可以吃囉？
Thanks, Senshi!
謝謝你，先西！
What does it taste like?
是什麼味道？
At first, it tastes like dirt.
首先會有泥巴味
But as you savor it,
仔細品嚐後
it's like this magical blend of green caterpillar, iron, and lemon.
會有將綠毛蟲、鐵和檸檬 奇妙地混合的味道
You're just comparing it to other things.
用了好多其他的東西比喻啊
There's no other way to describe it.
因為太難形容啦
Are you sure it's safe to eat magical creatures?
吃魔法生物真的沒問題嗎？
It might make you hear things and bleed from your nose again.
小心再出現幻聽或流鼻血等症狀
I wonder what's with those hallucinations.
那些幻聽是怎麼回事？
When we get back to town, you should really see a doctor
等我們回到鎮上 你就馬上去看醫生吧
for your head.
檢查一下腦
A doctor?
醫生？
Do you think it's some kind of illness?
我這是生病了嗎？
Is this another hallucination?
這也是幻覺？
Are you guys seeing this?
你們也看得見嗎？
I-I see it.
看得見
I mean, we're…
不如說我們…
under attack!
正在遭受攻擊！
Huh? What on earth?
啥？這是什麼？
It's just frog skin.
好像是青蛙的皮
Looks like these horns are just decorations on a helmet.
看來這對角也只是頭盔上的裝飾品
A child?
小孩子？
Some monsters disguise themselves as humans.
有些怪物有假扮成人的能力
Let's try killing one to see if they'll reveal their true colors--
我來殺掉其中一個 看看他們會不會露出真面目…
Don't, Maizuru.
住手，舞鶴
I know them.
是我認識的人
-Shuro!
-修洛！
Shuro, long time no see!
修洛，好久不見！
What a pleasant surprise to run into you here!
沒想到會在這裡見到你，真開心！
Did you lose weight?
你是不是稍微瘦了？
Thanks, Shuro!
謝啦，修洛！
Glad to see you're doing well.
你看起來過得不錯，太好了
Goodness! How forward of him!
天啊！這傢伙還一副熟人的嘴臉！
Oh, let me introduce you.
哦，我來介紹一下
This is Senshi.
這位是先西
Senshi, meet Shuro, our former party member.
先西，他是以前和我同隊的修洛
Shuro? Who's that?
修洛？誰啊？
They probably mean Young Master Toshiro.
是指俊朗少爺吧
Toshuro?
俊洛？
Let's continue our conversation sitting down.
別站著說話了，大家坐下來聊吧
We were just having a meal.
我們正好在吃飯呢
Would you all like to…
各位夥伴們也…
Huh? You've got quite a big group!
什麼？還真是大陣仗啊
Hey, Kabru.
我說啊，喀布爾
Is that…
那是…
Nice to meet you.
幸會啊
You're Laios, aren't you?
你就是萊歐斯先生吧？
Yeah.
對
Nice to meet you.
很高興認識你
How long has it been?
我們已經多久沒見啦？
Hey, Kabru.
等等，喀布爾
It's them, right?
就是那些傢伙吧？
The ones who stole our stuff.
是他們偷了我們的東西
What will you do?
怎麼辦？
Nothing.
不怎麼辦
Huh?
什麼？
What did we come all the way here for?
那我們是為了什麼 才到這種地方來啊？
I wanted to meet them.
我一直很想見他們一面
Huh?
什麼？
I doubt asking them about the treasure will help.
寶石的事，可能問了也無濟於事
He didn't look guilty even when he saw us.
他看到我們也沒露出內疚的神情
Either he doesn't remember, or we're mistaken.
他可能是忘了我們 不然就是我們誤會
Or maybe the treasure itself was a trap.
或者寶藏本身就是個圈套
Or maybe all of them.
不然就是以上皆是
Are you saying we made this trip for nothing?
那我們豈不是白忙一場了？
Don't be hasty.
別著急
Give me a bit more time.
再給我一點時間吧
Don't you want to find out how they managed to get here
你也想知道他們究竟是怎麼到達這裡
and what they plan to do in the future?
之後又有什麼打算，對吧？
So, you've been on this level for a while now?
這麼說來你也在這一層 待了一段時間囉？
Yeah.
是啊
We kept going around in circles,
我們一直在同個地方繞圈子
and when we got out, we were back at the entrance.
想說終於脫困了，結果卻回到入口處
We got lost a lot too.
我們也迷路了很久
But Chilchuck found patterns in the shifts,
不過奇爾查克發現迷宮變動的規則
and that's how we finally made it here.
我們最終才能走到這裡
I see.
這樣啊
Anyway, Shuro, you…
話說回來，修洛，你啊…
You lech!
真是個色鬼！
Are they the connections you mentioned?
她們就是你說要找的幫手啊？
Lucky you!
挺會享受的嘛！
They're just retainers.
她們都是自家人
They're quite skilled, though.
都是有實力的強者
I'm sorry for leaving the party.
抱歉之前我選擇離隊
But when I realized Falin was missing up on the surface,
不過當我在地表發現法琳沒有回來時
I thought this was the best way to get back into the dungeon and find her.
為了重返迷宮找她 我判斷這是最好的做法
Forgive me.
對不起
It's fine. There was no other way.
沒關係，這也沒辦法
But I'm surprised you went back into the dungeon right after that.
不過我沒料到 你們竟在那之後馬上回到迷宮
Wasn't it a little rash?
是否有些過於輕率了？
What would you have done if someone got hurt again?
要是又有其他人受傷的話該怎麼辦？
Just so you know,
恕我直言
the four of us even defeated the Red Dragon!
我們四人可是協力打倒了炎龍喔！
What?!
什麼？
The Red Dragon?
炎龍？
A-And what about her?
那麼她怎麼樣了？
Shuro!
修洛！
Young Master!
少爺！
I beg you, please eat and get some sleep!
拜託您了，請好好吃飯和睡覺
At this rate, your body will break down!
這樣下去身體會不堪負荷的
You're pushing yourself that hard?
你這麼亂來啊？
Look at how gaunt he is. You should've noticed.
看他這麼憔悴，你就該察覺到
You should get food and sleep, you know.
最好還是要好好吃飯和睡覺喔
I don't have time for that.
我哪有那種閒功夫
Shuro, eating isn't something you do when you have time.
修洛，吃飯可不是有空才做的事
It's only after having sleep and food
所謂的生物在獲取 充足的睡眠跟攝食後
that creatures can finally do what they want.
才有能力做自己想做的事
Have something to eat.
吃點東西吧
While you do, I'll fill you in on what happened.
用餐時我會告訴你至今發生的事
Fine.
我明白了
Can you prepare something, Maizuru?
能幫我準備一些吃的嗎？舞鶴
A meal! Prepare a meal!
要吃飯了！準備食物！
Tade, go fetch some water!
蓼，你去取水！
On it!
是！
Hien, Benichidori, get ready to cook rice.
飛燕、紅千鳥，你們去準備炊飯
Asebi, you…
馬醉木，你…
guard the Young Master.
負責保護少爺
I don't want anything strange mixed into the food.
我不希望餐點裡混進奇怪的東西
Well then, I'll get the fire going.
那麼老夫來幫忙生火吧
You are considerate.
你真機靈啊
I'll leave it to you, dwarf.
那就拜託你了，矮人
A meal, a meal!
吃飯…
This group is too big.
人有點多啊
It's not safe for so many people to gather in one place.
太多人聚集在一處不太好
Let's split up into three.
我們分散成三組吧
In that case,
好吧
Rin, dwarf,
阿鈴、矮人
frog woman!
蛙女！
What?!
蛙…
Everyone who can use magic, put up a barrier.
能使用魔法的人在這裡設置結界吧
Make sure no monsters disturb the Young Master while he eats.
讓魔物無法在少爺用餐時靠近
Let's work together, young lady.
請多指教囉，這位小姐
R-Right.
好的
Okay then,
好
Shuro, let's step away too.
修洛，我們也稍微離開一下吧
I'll give you a quick rundown.
我來簡單說明事情經過
I'll help support him.
我來扶他
Thanks.
謝謝
There's so much to do!
有太多事情要忙了！
In this case, who's more dangerous if left alone?
依現在這情況 獨自一人會最危險的是…
Monsters! Delicious! Awesome!
魔物！好好吃！超棒的！
Monsters! Cook! Eat!
魔物！料理！吃吧！
Eat this!
吃吧！
Die.
我要殺了你
Senshi, I'm coming with you!
先西，我也去你那邊！
Hey, aren't you overdoing it?
喂，是不是做得有點過頭啦？
The smoke…
煙…
After this meal, I must make him take a bath.
餐後得讓少爺泡個澡
Here?
在這泡澡？
Okay, Shuro, sit here.
來，修洛，坐這裡吧
Never mind that, just tell me what happened.
不必管我，快說吧 到底發生了什麼事？
After you and Namari left, we--
在和修洛、娜瑪莉分開後，我們…
Just give me the gist.
講重點就好
We defeated the Red Dragon, retrieved Falin, and revived her.
我們打倒了炎龍 奪回法琳並讓她復活
But on our way back, we were attacked by the lunatic magician,
但在回程途中被狂亂魔術師攻擊
and we lost her.
所以我們走散了
There was nothing more we could do on our own,
接下來憑我們幾人是難以應付的
so we decided to head back to the surface and ask for backup.
所以打算回到地面尋求支援
But we got lost and…
但卻迷路了…
But I'm glad we crossed paths with you, Shuro!
不過幸好在這裡遇到了修洛
Will you help us out?
能否助我們一臂之力呢？
Um, can I ask something?
那個，我可以發問嗎？
The lunatic magician is the one who created this dungeon, right?
狂亂魔術師就是 這座迷宮的製造者吧？
There are rumors and whispers about him,
雖然有許多關於他的傳聞與謠言
but no one who's seen him has ever returned.
但從來無人能在見過他後平安生還
How can you be sure it was him?
然而你為何斷定 對方就是狂亂魔術師呢？
Huh?
什麼？
Well, he sounded and acted like it.
這個嘛，因為行為舉止感覺滿像的啊
And how did you manage to escape?
而且你們又是如何脫身的呢？
It was thanks to Marcille…
多虧了瑪露希爾…
The mage in our party protected us.
我們的魔術師同伴努力救了我們
How exactly?
具體來說是怎麼做的？
Um…
呃…
Magic isn't my area of expertise, so I'm not sure.
魔法並非我的專業領域 所以我也不太確定
I see.
這樣啊
I have a question too.
我也可以問一下嗎？
Why were you munching on a brick?
你們為什麼在啃磚塊？
Huh?
什麼？
Oh, it's not what it seems.
哦，不是你想的那樣啦
That wasn't a brick.
我們啃的不是磚塊
It was part of a wall made from Dungeon Cleaners.
是迷宮清道夫形成的牆
We left all our food and money behind, right?
我們把糧食和錢 都留在深層了，對吧？
So to get down into the dungeon faster, we fed on monsters along the way.
所以為了趕緊潛入迷宮 就一路吃魔物存活至今
That…
那還真是…
is just hilarious!
有趣呢！
Huh?
什麼？
What was the tastiest thing you've eaten so far?
到目前為止吃過最好吃的是什麼呢？
You want to know?
想知道那點嗎？
That's a tough one.
難以抉擇啊
Kelpie, Living Armor…
水棲馬、會動的鎧甲…
No, it's got to be the Red Dragon!
不，應該是炎龍吧！
You ate the Red Dragon that ate your sister?
你還把吃了令妹的炎龍吃掉了？
Yeah.
是啊
Living Armor, though. Are there any edible parts?
話說會動的鎧甲有可食用的部分嗎？
That's a good question!
這是個好問題！
Actually, it's a colony of mollusks wearing a shell and…
那其實是帶殼的軟體生物…
Here, check out this sword.
你看看這把劍
The Cleaners are trying to eat Kensuke!
清道夫在吃劍助！
You just can't be too careful!
真不能大意啊！
By the way, if you're interested in monster cuisine,
對了，如果你對吃魔物有興趣的話
I'd be happy to treat you anytime.
隨時都可以招待你喔
Wow, I'd love that!
哇，那就麻煩你了！
Crap. This guy will actually take me up on it.
糟了，這傢伙真的會帶魔物來給我
So after she…
那麼她…
After Falin was revived, was she safe the last time you saw her?
法琳復活後 你最後見到她時，她還好嗎？
Yeah.
她很好
Any idea where she might be?
關於她的所在地，有頭緒了嗎？
There are plenty of places to hide on this level,
雖然這一層有許多藏身之處
but most of them are the orcs' base camps.
但大多是半獸人的據點
Oh, you don't have to worry about them.
哦，不用擔心半獸人的事
What?
什麼？
What did they taste like?
味道如何？
No!
不是啦！
It's a long story, but we're cooperating with them now.
因為一些原因 我們和他們現在是互助關係
Cooperating with them?
互助關係？
Has he forgotten that killing them is our duty as adventurers?
討伐半獸人好歹算是冒險者的義務吧
Anyway, about Falin's whereabouts,
關於法琳的所在地
she might be somewhere lower than this level.
也許她在比這裡更深層的地方
She could have been taken there.
可能被帶到那裡去了
Taken? Why?
被帶走了？為什麼？
Um…
其實…
Is it safe to tell Shuro?
對修洛應該可以說出實情吧？
Would you mind if I talked to him alone?
我想跟修洛單獨談一下
Sure, I'll step out.
好，那我離席了
So?
然後呢？
Field ration pellets aren't bad, but having them every day?
兵糧丸沒有不好 不過每天吃的話不太妥當
Sometimes, you need something warm in your belly.
偶爾還是需要吃溫熱的食物啊
I agree.
我同意
A meal should be more than about filling the stomach.
所謂的吃飯並不是能果腹就好
I see you have sense, dwarf.
你這矮人還挺明事理的嘛
The Young Master was often sick as a child.
少爺自幼體弱多病
He also had a small appetite, which worried everyone.
吃得又少，令周圍的人都很不安
But he always had a hearty appetite for whatever I made him.
但不管是何時，唯有我舞鶴做的 少爺總是吃得特別多
Even during missions, I was often sent to the kitchen.
執行任務的期間 我常被叫去廚房工作
He was such a well-behaved child, it made me concerned.
少爺還是個懂事到令人擔心的好孩子
This is the first time he's ever made a selfish request.
從小到大只任性了這麼一次
Please, Maizuru.
拜託你了，舞鶴
There's someone I want to save.
我有想救的人
Lend me your aid.
請協助我
I never imagined he'd become
沒想到他會在修練過程中
infatuated with a Northern girl on his training journey.
被北方女給迷住
How do I convince him to move on?
該怎麼說他才肯放棄呢？
You want him to move on?
你想讓他放棄嗎？
I've been tasked by the lord to care for the Young Master.
我受當家委任，需照顧少爺
I can't let my emotions dictate my actions.
可不能感情用事
Then why are you doing what you're doing?
那麼你現在在做什麼？
If you have preserved foods, you don't have to bother with cooking.
既然有儲備口糧 就沒必要這麼費力地調理食物
I know why he had an appetite for your cooking only.
為什麼只有你做的食物 他吃得特別多？
I know what you put into them.
你在裡頭加了什麼？ 這些老夫可是知道的
Huh?
什麼？
It was love.
那就是愛情
What is that supposed to mean?
那算什麼啊？
Were you trying to be clever?
你是自認為說出了什麼金玉良言？
But yes, I suppose it's a little too late now.
不過也對，事已至此
Depending on how things turn out,
視情況發展
perhaps I can speak on his behalf.
或許可以出言幫他一把
TSUGUYOSHI NAKAMOTO
（半本繼義）
TOSHITSUGU NAKAMOTO
（半本俊繼）
NOW, TOSHIRO NAKAMOTO
（半本俊朗，現在這代）
FALIRO NAKAMOTO
（半本法琳朗）
It's using different art materials!
連畫材都變了！
I don't think that's likely just yet.
我認為目前還不太可能
Good. This will do.
很好，差不多了吧
It's ready.
完成了
AN EASTERN MEAL
（東方餐點）
Now then, let us serve it while it's hot!
快點，得讓少爺趁熱享用！
What are you two doing here?
你們怎麼在這種地方？
They wanted to talk privately.
他們說有事要單獨談論
Young Master, I'm coming in.
少爺，我進去囉
Young Master!
少爺！
What happened?
究竟發生了什麼事？
Did this man try something?
這個男人做了什麼嗎？
Well? What happened?!
這是怎樣？他們是怎麼了？
Sorry. We don't know.
不好意思，我們也不知道
Black magic.
黑魔法
This man used black magic to revive a woman using monster flesh.
這傢伙使用黑魔法 用魔物的血肉讓一個女人復活
Black…?
黑…
How could you?
為什麼要做那種事？
Do you even realize what you've done?
你明白自己做了什麼嗎？
Anyone involved with black magic,
和黑魔法扯上關係的人
no matter their motives or degree of magic, is a serious criminal!
無論理由和程度，都是重罪！
They're locked up in the dark until they die,
會終生被關在照不到陽光的地方
and even their corpses never return.
連屍骨都要不回來
If the elves of the west find out, who knows what will happen to her?
要是西方的精靈得知此事 你認為她會遭到什麼對待？
That is, if word gets out from this dungeon.
前提是“如果事情傳到了迷宮外”
And I know you will never tell anyone about this.
而你絕不會把這件事說出去
Right?
對吧？
It was the only way.
我別無選擇
Please understand, Shuro.
希望你能諒解，修洛
Black magic?
黑魔法？
This is way worse than I thought.
出現了比想像中更不妙的東西呢
What's going to happen now?
這下事態會如何演變？
Lord Delgal…
迪爾加路大人…
I must find him.
我必須找到他
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：郭芷彤